翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
Turns out the add and get will be perfectly fast.
事实证明添加和获取将非常快
Remove will be slow.
删除将会很慢
Now you might say, if you're just kind of casually watching and not thinking very hard,
如果你没有很认真地思考，可能会说
how can that be?
这怎么可能呢？
We have last here, so we'll just aim our big giant deletion death ray at this thing.
我们的 last 就像巨大的死亡射线对准这东西
Shoot it.
开火
50 explodes.
50就爆炸了
We don't have to ever think about it.
根本不用多想
But that's not what removing means. Right?
但这不是删除的意思，对吗？
It's not how we delete.
不是这样删除的
Deletion, in fact, will be about changing these two pointers in red.
实际上，删除是改变这两个红色的指针
So specifically, if we want to delete this node,
具体来讲，如果我们想要删除这个节点
it means, first, we need to set this to null.
首先，我们需要将这个设置为 null
I guess I'll just leave it null.
还是把它留为 null 吧
And I also need to point last at this box here.
我还需要 last 指着这个盒子
So, in effect, in order to delete the final item on the list,
因此为了删除 List 上的最后一项
we need to somehow know where the second to last item is
我们需要以某种方式知道倒数第二项在哪里
because we need to be able to change this and we need to point last at the second to last item.
因为我们需要能够改变它，从最后一项指向倒数第二项
So in other words, in order to delete from the end full list,
换句话说，为了从 List 末尾删除
even if we have a last pointer,
即使我们有 last 指针
we're still going to have to iterate to find the second to last item.
仍然需要迭代才能找到倒数第二项
So why can't we just cache the second to last item?
那为什么不只缓存倒数第二项呢？
Well, it turns out you can just inductively work your way along and say,
事实证明，你可以顺藤摸瓜
well, in that case, we'd actually need to find the third to last thing
那样的们实际上需要找到倒数第三项
in order to set the second to last pointer, and so forth.
以便设置倒数第二个指针，依此类推
So that approach of just adding a single cached value is not going to do it for us.
因此，仅仅添加一个缓存值的方法对我们来说是行不通的
OK.
好
So to get from here, this state to the deletion state,
所以从这里开始，从这个状态到删除状态
we need more information than we could possibly store just in some little cache up at the top level.
我们需要更多的信息，而不是仅仅存储在顶层的某个小缓存中
So what I'd like you to do now is consider what could I do?
我想让你们现在考虑一下我能做些什么？
Right, this is a good start.
对，这是个好的开始
I'll tell you that.
我会告诉你的
But what can we do to the overall structure of the list,
我们能对 List 的整体结构做些什么
so that remove last is also fast?
让删除最后一项也很快
So think about that a little.
稍微想一想这点
You have to do something else other than just adding a pointer up here.
你不能只在这添加一个指针
That's not going to get you anywhere.
那对你没多少帮助
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
So think about what else you might do.
所以想一想还可以做些什么